FEDERICO SALINAS

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

E-mail federico.salinas0328@gmail.com

Phone (815) 909-7133

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/federico-salinas-82b648195/

Portfolio federicosalinas.com

GitHub https://github.com/salinasfez?tab=repositories

Software developer committed to creating the most efficient solutions to routine methods in order to save companies money and provide users with a seamless experience. I focus on leading by example and keeping my team moving forward. In the workplace, I believe that by supporting and elevating my coworkers, we all find greater success. Honesty, hard work, and gratitude are my lifestyle.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML 5 | CSS3 | MONGO DB | RUBY ON RAILS

BOOTSTRAP | JAVASCRIPT | SQL

REACT | JQUERY | EXPRESS | NODE.JS

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering I August 2019-February 2020 GENERAL ASSEMBLY

- Completed 6 month learning the latest and most efficient technologies in the industry.
- Built functional applications from the ground up.
- Solved constant bugs through process of elimination and by using key resources provided by instructors.

Bakery/Deli Manager I April 2018-present BOCKWINKEL'S

- Enhanced product quality and presentation of items
- · Improved team performance and productivity.
- Increased sales from 1.8% to 2.5% of the company's total sales.

Head Baker I December 2007-April 2018 SWISS MAID BAKERY

- Specialized in commercial from-scratch baking.
- Methodically re-arranged daily routines to minimize down time.
- Mentored and developed new employees.

PROJECTS

Mercy Clinic Appointment Center

https://mercy-appointment-center.herokuapp.com/appointments

Tech used: React, Express, Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Node JS

Budgeting Application

https://federico-budget-app.herokuapp.com/

Tech used: React, Express, Javascript, HTML5 Bootstrap, MongoDB, Node JS

EDUCATION

Software Engineering I 2019-2020 GENERAL ASSEMBLY

McHenry County College I 2012-2014
COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS